{"tossups": [{"question": "This man was legendarily forced to sell his belongings after his son Caeso fled to the Etruscans. Barbatus called upon this man to thwart Spurius Maelius\u2019 plans to buy the crown of Rome in 439 BC. This man, who rose to his highest post after the Aequi attacked Tusculum, was victorious at the Battle of Mount Algidus, after which he chose to return to his farm and resigned his dictatorial powers just fifteen days after receiving them. For ten points, name this famously honorable Roman statesman who inspired the name of a city in Ohio.", "answer": "Lucius Quinctius<b> Cincinnatus</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Min Chueh Chang helped Gregory Pincus create a product meant for this purpose.<em> The Woman Rebel</em> was written by an activist supporting this action who was prosecuted under the Federal Comstock Law. Diaphragms were illegally smuggled into the United States to aid with this action, which was promoted by a Brownsville clinic that opened in 1916. Margaret Sanger and Planned Parenthood advocate for, for ten points, what type of medical care that assists in family planning and can prevent abortions?", "answer": "<b> contraception</b> (accept<b> birth control</b>; accept<b> family planning</b> before mentioned; prompt on (women\u2019s) medical care; do not accept or prompt on abortion)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man deposed Alakeshwara of the Kotte Kingdom during a military expedition to Ceylon. He helped oversee the construction of the Porcelain Tower after he was reassigned as commander of Nanjing, after his influence waned under Hongxi [hong-shee]. This man\u2019s most famous feats were performed under the Yongle Emperor, to whose court he brought a Malindi giraffe. For ten points, name this admiral of the Ming Dynasty known for his seven \u201ctreasure voyages.\u201d", "answer": "<b> Zheng</b> He ([jung huh], but be lenient) Page 1", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This battle was preceded by a failed peace negotiation at the castle Montebello and the losing side\u2019s failure to make new allies at Ciavenna. Wichmann of Magdeburg reinforced one side at Como prior to this battle. Guido da Landriano led a courageous defense of the cross of Aribert of Milan in this battle with the aid of the \u201cCompany of Death.\u201d It led to the Treaty of Constance, where the Holy Roman Empire agreed not to interfere in Italian affairs. For ten points, name this 1176 battle in which the Lombard League defeated Frederick Barbarossa.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Legnano</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Max Nordau promoted this movement in an address calling for a \u201cmuscular\u201d version of its supporters. Ze\u2019ev Jabotinsky founded a \u201crevisionist\u201d version of this movement with the creation of Betar. The Uganda Scheme tried to give up a portion of British East Africa in support of this movement. The Balfour Declaration, given to Lord Rothschild, reaffirmed this movement\u2019s desire for aliyah. For ten points, name this movement that, at its creation in the 19th century, sought to establish a Jewish homeland in Israel.", "answer": "<b> Zion</b>ism", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This woman was allegedly introduced to her husband by Aaron Burr, who frequented the boarding house run by this woman\u2019s mother. This woman holds the distinction of being the only First Lady given an honorary Congressional seat. Because he was widowed, Thomas Jefferson often relied on this First Lady to serve as hostess during official events. For ten points, name this First Lady who directed her family\u2019s slave to save the Landsdowne portrait of George Washington during the War of 1812.", "answer": "Dolley Todd<b> Madison</b> (accept Dolley Todd<b> Payne</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A former member of this movement named Jeremiah Brandreth led the failed Pentrich Rising, which wanted to wipe out the national debt by starting an uprising in Derbyshire. This movement\u2019s namesake, a weaver in Anstey, used a hammer in his most notorious act. The Frame Breaking Act of 1812 allowed the British government to execute seventy members of this movement, which began in Nottingham among textile workers worried about their job security. For ten points, name this 19th century movement that violently opposed innovation and lends its name to a modern term for people that do not embrace new technology.", "answer": "<b> Luddite</b>s", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "A woman who married into this family commissioned Julia Morgan to embellish a Mining Building named for her husband. Another member of this family hired Morgan to design a home for this family near San Simeon that includes space for what was the world\u2019s largest private zoo. A Greek Theater named for this family is still in use on the University of California Berkeley campus, where a member of this family named Patty was kidnapped in 1974. For ten points, name this American family once headed by journalism magnate William Randolph.", "answer": "<b> Hearst</b> (accept Phoebe Elizabeth Apperson<b> Hearst</b>; accept Patricia Campbell \u201cPatty\u201d<b>Hearst</b>; accept William Randolph<b> Hearst</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In this state, Frank Canton led a band of Texans known as Wolcott\u2019s Regulators in Powder River Country during the Johnston County War. Thomas J. Walsh led an investigation of a scandal named for a location in this state; as a result, Albert Fall was imprisoned for accepting bribes. The Teapot Dome oil field is in this state, where the Great Western Cattle Trail passed by Fort Laramie. The first state to grant suffrage to women was, for ten points, what state that is governed from Cheyenne?", "answer": "<b> Wyoming</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This composer wrote his choral piece<em> Trois Chansons</em> while waiting to be enlisted in the Air Force. This composer noted that \u201cthe dead are sad enough, in their eternal silence\u201d when reflecting on his 1917 six-movement piece that pays memory to his deceased friends. After Paul Wittgenstein lost his right arm during World War I, this composer wrote a<em> Piano Concerto for the Left Hand</em>. A repetitive melody plays over a snare drum ostinato in a piece by, for ten points, what French composer of<em> Le Tombeau de Couperin</em> and<em> Bolero</em>?", "answer": "(Joseph-)Maurice<b> Ravel</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "This man died on a diplomatic mission to Russia after his ship, the<em> HMS Hampshire</em>, hit a German mine. This man\u2019s infighting with George Curzon caused Curzon to resign as Viceroy of India. This man agreed with Jean-Baptiste Marchand to fly three flags over an African fort during a tense territorial standoff in 1898. A 1914 recruitment poster demanded that this man \u201cwants you\u201d to join the army. Charles Gordon\u2019s death was \u201cavenged\u201d by, for ten points, what British officer who won the 1898 Battle of Omdurman in Sudan?", "answer": "Horatio Herbert<b> Kitchener</b>, 1st Earl Kitchener", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>After a leader of this event was shot, his assassin declared that \u201cI have killed a man, but I am not a murderer;\u201d the courts eventually found Soghomon Tehlirian not guilty of that</b> <b>killing in Berlin. Operation Nemesis sought to assassinate Djemal and (+)</b> <b>Talaat for this</b> <b>event after the two pashas marched their victims to Deir ez-Zor. The Battle of Sarikamish was blamed on a certain group aiding (*)</b> Russia in World War I, leading to, for ten points, what genocide perpetrated by the Ottoman government and denied by modern Turkey?", "answer": "<b> Armenian genocide</b> (accept<b> Armenia</b> alone after \u201cgenocide\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>With Bill Nichols, this man sponsored a bill to reorganize the Department of Defense. This man\u2019s policies were targeted by the \u201cIce Cream\u201d Ad and another ad that ended \u201cWe</b> <b>must (+)</b> <b>love each other, or we must die.\u201d In one campaign, this man\u2019s slogan \u201cIn your</b> <b>heart, you know he\u2019s right\u201d was mocked by his opponent\u2019s slogan \u201cIn your gut, you know he\u2019s nuts.\u201d The book</b><em><b> Conscience of a</b></em><b> (*) </b> <em>Conservative</em> was written by, for ten points, what five-time senator from Arizona who lost in a landslide election to Lyndon Johnson in 1964?", "answer": "Barry<b> Goldwater</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This family\u2019s first ruler was pressured to retire to the Stoudion monastery on the advice of Michael Psellos. A history of this family was written by Anna and describes the suspicion</b> <b>this family held towards (+)</b> <b>Bohemond of Taranto. This family\u2019s most famous ruler sent</b> <b>Bohemond of Taranto. This family\u2019s most famous ruler sent</b> <b>his ambassadors to the Council of Piacenza after a defeat at (*)</b> <b>his ambassadors to the Council of Piacenza after a defeat at (*)</b> Manzikert. In response to Seljuk expansion, Pope Urban II called for knights to come aid this family. For ten points, name this Byzantine ruling family that, during the First Crusade, was led by Alexius I.", "answer": "<b> Komnenos</b> dynasty (accept<b> Komnenid</b>s or<b> Komnenoi</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The first holder of this post lasted only thirteen days in power after William Fox defeated Henry Sewell in election. Holders of this post refused to accept the autonomy offered in the</b> <b>1931 Statute of Westminster until George (+)</b> <b>Forbes took power. Finland\u2019s Sanna Marin</b> <b>beat a record set by the current holder of this post as the world\u2019s youngest female leader. This office was held for thirteen years by Richard (*)</b> Seddon, who used his tenure to annex the Cook Islands and buy land from the native Maori. Jacinda Ardern currently holds, for ten points, what post that heads a government in Wellington?", "answer": "<b> Prime Minister of New Zealand</b> (accept<b> premier of New Zealand</b>; prompt on partial answers) ", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>Jean le Maingre was captured at this battle while commanding the vanguard. This battle\u2019s winning monarch allegedly had part of his crown struck off while defending his</b> <b>brother, Duke (+)</b> <b>Humphrey. The winning side in this battle, fearing an imminent</b> <b>attack, ordered the killing of all their prisoners, though they had earlier withstood an attack on their (*)</b> baggage train. Wooden stakes in muddy ground rendered the losing side\u2019s knights ineffective against the longbow in, for ten points, what 1415 victory for Henry V on St. Crispin\u2019s Day during the Hundred Years\u2019 War?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Agincourt</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}